Your Highness!
So you're the coward who shot
that arrow from the shadows.
Talk.
Who sent you?
Stop the carriage! Stop!
The horse is spooked!
The horse is spooked! It won't stop!
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 12=
Gu Qingshu,
looks like I went too
easy on you last time.
You clearly haven't learned your lesson.
Since you want to kill me,
why not make it quick?
Why don't you kill me?
Remember today.
If there's a next time,
you won't even have the chance
to beg for mercy.
Your Highness, why are you here?
I was hoping to invite you to dinner.
Young Master Shen said
you came to Fahua Temple.
So I came to try my luck.
Did you come looking for me,
or have you been following me all along?
Both.
Who else but you
could make me forget about dinner,
ignore my frail health,
and disregard the cold of the night,
just to see you?
I originally thought
that Young Master Bu
was quite the flirt.
But I didn't expect
that compared to the Crown Prince,
he's not even close.
Why don't we trouble Young Master Bu
to hunt some game for us?
Me?
I like rabbit meat.
As you command.
It might take a while
for Young Master Bu to hunt.
Why don't we take a walk together?
Let's take shelter
in that pavilion over there.
All right.
♪A wall that collapses at a single push♪
♪Frost that melts at a single smile♪
♪How can you be this wonderful♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
I've loved the rain since I was a child.
If it rains at night,
sleeping to the sound of the rain
is especially peaceful.
If it rains during the day,
listening to the sound of the rain
feels as if all my sorrows
can be cleared away
like clouds parting for the sun,
and simply vanish.
As far as I know,
it rarely rains in the northwest.
Youyou.
In front of me,
you can say anything.
But, Youyou,
you must be wary of those
with ill intentions.
Now that my coming-of-age ceremony
is complete,
when should we report to my father?
Let's wait a few days.
My brother
hasn't agreed to this marriage yet.
I have to persuade him.
If Young Master Shen doesn't agree,
will you
change your mind?
We are allies.
Since we have an agreement,
I will never go back on my word.
Good.
Then I will be like this rain.
Though it is gentle,
it can wear away stone.
I will carve our promise
on the Three-life Stone,
never to be broken.
(Memorial Tablet for the Late Lady Gu)
Brother-in-law!
You can't go in.
Don't stop me.
His Highness said that he won't see you.
Please calm down. Calm down.
Brother-in-law.
Calm down.
I don't want to marry
into the Chu family.
You may all leave.
- Yes.
The Chu family,
though not a prominent clan,
is an upstanding and noble family.
Young Master Chu is a man
of upstanding character.
A true gentleman.
This marriage
is one I chose for you myself.
I won't marry him.
I want to stay by your side,
Brother-in-law.
Otherwise...
Otherwise, I will die here today.
Even if you die,
you will be buried
in the Chu family's ancestral tomb.
Just because I provoked Shen Xihe,
you're treating me like this?
If not for the fact
that you are of the Gu bloodline,
for such audacity,
I would have dealt with you long ago.
You're so cruel to me.
(Prince Xin's Manor)
Young Lady Qingshu,
are you all right?
I threatened to kill myself,
but I still couldn't convince
my brother-in-law.
Then,
does this mean you have
to marry into the Chu family?
(Prince Xin's Manor)
Why is it that she, Gu Qingzhi,
could marry a prince,
while I'm just a pawn
at everyone's mercy?
What should we do now?
The Empress Dowager's maternal family
once had ties with the ancestors
of the Gu family.
Because of this connection,
the Empress Dowager
takes great pity on me.
She allows me to visit her often
at Yong'an Hall to keep her company.
If I can make a prince
fall for me,
I'll have a way
to ask the Empress Dowager
to decree a marriage.
His Majesty is a devotedly filial son.
As long as the Empress Dowager
makes the request,
he will surely not refuse.
I see. You've already
thought so far ahead.
Pinning all one's hopes
on a single man
is the height of foolishness.
In a few days,
the Empress Dowager and His Majesty
will hold an investiture ceremony
for Shen Xihe.
All the princes will be in attendance.
(Duke of Wei's Manor)
Greetings, Your Highness.
I have something
I'd like to discuss
with the Commandery Princess alone.
Your Highness, to what do I owe
the pleasure of your visit?
Shu...
is reckless
and has repeatedly offended you.
As her brother-in-law,
I have been remiss in my duty
to discipline her.
I came today specifically to apologize.
I hope you can be magnanimous
and not stoop to her level.
When I saved her,
it was only to preserve
the Gu family bloodline.
Recently,
I have already arranged
a good marriage for her.
Once she is married
and leaves the imperial capital,
she will no longer appear before you
and cause you any displeasure.
She may have been offensive,
but I have already disciplined her.
Let's drop the matter.
There's no need to dwell on it,
Your Highness.
Since you arrived in the capital,
you threw Prince Kang's sister,
Lady Xiao, out of the manor,
made Young Lady Hu reap what she sowed,
and showed no mercy
to Princess Pingling.
I thought you were the type
to avenge every wrong.
Why...
are you making an exception
for Gu Qingshu?
People cherish old friendships.
I was good friends
with her sister, Qingzhi.
As for the last remaining member
of the Gu family,
is showing some mercy
so strange?
You are truly righteous.
I am impressed.
This painting
is my apology.
I hope you will accept it.
(Qing)
These are among
the few remaining paintings
my wife left behind.
She was aloof and proud.
Immensely talented,
but she rarely showed it.
It is indeed a fine painting.
This is a kind and generous gesture
of yours.
In that case, I shall accept it.
I'll always remember
the first time I met Qingzhi.
That day, I went hunting in the woods.
On my way back,
heavy rain started to fall.
So I found a woodshed to take shelter.
And I happened to meet her there.
It was in that moment that I understood
that when some people meet,
a single glance can be an eternity,
etched into your very soul.
The brilliant glow of a thousand suns
paled in comparison.
From then on,
she was engraved upon my heart.
By the way,
may I ask you to give me
my late wife's letters
as a keepsake?
Those are letters
between Qingzhi and me.
I cannot give them to you.
In that case,
I won't insist.
If you ever face difficulties
in the future,
just bring the letters and find me.
I will do everything
in my power to help.
I don't need anyone's help.
And I certainly won't use
Qingzhi's letters
to ask for favors.
Zhen Zhu.
These are all the letters
between Qingzhi and me.
(For Xihe)
Why are you doing this?
The letters are mine.
It's my decision what to do with them.
The painting is also mine.
I can do what I want with it, too.
All burned.
I did it so that you wouldn't cling
to any lingering hopes.
Lest you do something outrageous again.
The dead are gone.
Why let these inanimate objects
tie you down,
wallowing in memories you can't escape?
The day after tomorrow, His Majesty
will personally
hold my investiture ceremony.
I won't see you out.
(Qing)
You're so cruel.
You're truly so cruel.
But this ruthlessness
makes me incredibly happy.
Because you're just like
you were before.
In this world, a lady
can only live happily and freely
if she is unfeeling.
A heartless person
cannot have feelings.
Your affection...
Qingqing!
- is destined to be misplaced.
- Qingqing!
Do you recognize
what this is?
Changqing!
- Calm down.
- Tell me now!
I hope you...
Who are you?
will abandon that incredible delusion.
Stop chasing shadows.
All burned.
I did it so that you wouldn't cling
to any lingering hopes.
It's been so long.
(Qing)
Shen Yueshan, the Duke of Wei,
guards northwest with outstanding merit
and service.
His eldest daughter, Xihe,
is gentle, virtuous,
and of graceful bearing.
She is hereby specially conferred the
title of Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
Having now received my favor
and entered the capital,
she has abided by the rites
with reverence and propriety,
greatly pleasing
both the Empress Dowager and I.
Therefore, a special investiture
ceremony shall be held in Yong'an Hall.
(Ning)
Besides, she is granted a golden plaque.
With this, she may enter and exit
the palace grounds day or night.
On urgent matters, she may
report directly to the throne
without being announced.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Congratulations, Xihe. His Majesty
personally conferred your title.
Good things are coming.
You're definitely going
to marry the Crown Prince.
Then I wish you a happy married life.
May every day be blissful.
Well, I'll be on my way.
Zhaoning.
Princess Anling,
is something on your mind?
It's nothing.
Is it about Young Master Bu?
As for Young Master Bu,
I gave up the idea
of marrying him long ago.
There are many other fine young men
in the imperial capital.
You can take your time to choose.
There's something you don't know,
Zhaoning.
Actually, it's harder for a princess
to marry someone she truly desires.
How so?
After a princess marries
into her husband's family,
her husband and parents-in-law
must pay their respects to her daily.
My husband can't take concubines.
To enter the princess's chambers,
he must first get her permission.
Some sons of noble families
and prominent households
are actually unwilling
to marry a princess.
Especially someone like Young Master Bu,
from a family of generals,
who is expected to achieve great things
in the future.
So,
I've never blamed him
for not taking an interest in me.
You are able
to understand others' difficulties.
You don't force things or hold grudges.
That is truly a rare
and admirable quality.
Among the young men
of noble and prominent families,
there are many who wish to marry you.
Fate will surely bring you
the right person one day.
Sometimes I wonder
why it must be a match
of equal social standing?
Among the commoners,
there are countless talented men
as well.
You seem so troubled.
Could it be you already
have someone in mind?
No.
I was just lost in thought.
I can't hide anything from you.
The other day,
when I went to visit Changqing,
I met an exceptionally talented
young man from a humble background.
I fell for him at first sight.
But his social standing is far too low.
Unless he passes
the imperial examinations,
it's absolutely impossible.
I know it's impossible,
but I just can't forget him.
Is falling in love
really a good thing?
Falling in love can bring pain,
but it can also give rise
to a kind of joy.
A lifelong,
incomparable joy.
Your Highness, you've been leading me
around this garden aimlessly.
What exactly is your intention?
You've come from afar,
Young Master Shen,
and I have yet to fulfill
my duties as a host.
Today, we'll start with Yong'an Hall,
and I'll show you the charms
of the imperial capital.
Originally, you would have been able
to see the splendor of Changyu today.
You mean Prince Yu, who is hailed
as the most handsome man in the capital?
The very same.
I heard he has the grace of an immortal
and is exceptionally handsome.
He also sought to marry my sister.
That is true.
However,
we only found out later
that Changyu's beloved
was a courtesan from Yunshao House,
Bian Xianyi.
Unfortunately,
they are now separated by death.
Coupled with the death of his mother,
Changyu requested
to guard the imperial tombs
to live out the rest of his days.
How dare he!
If he already had someone he loved,
how dare he seek to marry my sister?
Don't be angry, Young Master Shen.
Let's go this way.
The scenery is better.
Today, seeing the noble ladies
vying to please
Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
you seem a little disappointed.
I just don't want those people
to compare me with my elder sister.
In your veins flows the blood
of the imperial Xiao family
and the renowned Shen family.
Your noble status
is something other ladies
can only dream of but never attain.
To some people,
the more they can't compare,
the more they'll pick at others'
misfortunes to elevate themselves.
Someone, help!
Someone fell into the water!
Help!
Yingruo!
Save her, quickly!
- Hurry! Hurry!
- Hurry!
Hurry up.
- Your Highness.
Hold it, Your Highness!
I apologize for alarming you,
Father.
Please forgive me.
Changmin,
what exactly happened?
Reporting to you, Father.
Just now, I was passing
through the courtyard
and saw Young Lady Shen
fall into the water.
In the heat of the moment,
I jumped into the water to save her.
Young Lady Shen,
are you unharmed?
I am unharmed.
Thank you for your concern,
Your Majesty.
How did you suddenly lose your footing
and fall in?
Reporting to Your Majesty.
My lady was feeling a bit stuffy
and wanted to get some fresh air here.
A cat appeared out of nowhere
and lunged right at her.
My lady was startled,
and that's how she fell into the water.
Go summon the imperial physician
lest she catch a cold.
Father,
I have one more matter to discuss,
and I implore you to grant my request.
Speak freely.
I dare not hide it.
Young Lady Shen and I
indeed had
intimate physical contact in the water.
After today,
who knows what kind of
gossip will spread
throughout the imperial capital?
I'm willing to take responsibility
for my recklessness.
I wish
to ask for Young Lady Shen's hand
in marriage
as my second wife.
Young Lady Shen,
what are your thoughts?
Thank you for saving my life,
Your Highness.
But I have been a study companion
in the palace since I was young.
I have always regarded you
as an older brother.
As for my reputation,
the innocent have nothing to fear.
I do not mind.
Ruo.
Your Highness, you are of noble status.
But I am simple-minded.
I am afraid I would be unworthy
of your kind intentions.
Well, in that case,
Changmin,
rest assured.
I will issue an order
to ensure no rumors spread
within the palace.
Thank you, Father.
Changmin once asked
for Xihe's hand in marriage.
But as you can see now,
he is also interested
in your half-sister, Shen Yingruo,
and is unwilling to let her go either.
He's trying to have it both ways.
His heart is fickle.
How despicable.
Young Master Shen, let's continue.
We're still walking around?
Today, royals, nobles,
and distinguished families,
men and women alike,
are all gathered here.
You will not only see
the beautiful scenery,
but also witness many instances
of true, mutual affection.
This way, please.
I was too heavy-handed
and injured your cat.
What compensation would you like,
Your Ladyship?
I will do my utmost to provide it.
Don't worry about it, Your Highness.
I wasn't watching it properly.
It startled you.
You were only acting in self-defense.
You are not to blame.
How about
I send it to be checked
to see if anything is wrong?
We can also have the palace veterinarian
treat it right away.
Thank you for your concern,
Your Highness.
I have a physician at my residence
who specifically cares for it.
I will take it back
to my residence shortly.
In your heart,
even the life of a cat
is not to be taken lightly.
For that alone,
your virtue
surpasses that of countless men.
Please.
Gu Qingshu, a master of manipulation.
A cat, a hint of apology,
and a display of reasonableness.
This back and forth
is enough for her
to gradually get acquainted
with Prince Lie.
She wants to marry Prince Lie?
Changqing is cold
and indifferent to her.
She must have changed her target.
Changying is dashing and wealthy.
He is naturally a prime candidate
for a husband.
Even so,
Prince Lie would never fall for her.
To have a cat pounce on Changying
at just the right moment
without arousing any suspicion,
a lady like that
cannot be underestimated.
Even if she failed this time,
Gu Qingshu definitely
has other tricks up her sleeve.
Your imperial capital
is truly too chaotic.
As you know,
Prince Ning's heart belongs to another.
Prince Xin cannot let go
of his late wife.
Prince Yu has lost his beloved.
- Prince Lie...
- Prince Lie wishes to marry Xihe,
promising to never
take another lady in his life.
That's right.
Prince Lie is indeed devoted
to the Commandery Princess.
But like the other princes,
he is the ideal husband
for all noble ladies.
When the time comes,
they will all be like Gu Qingshu,
using endless schemes and tricks.
If Commandery Princess marries him,
her future days will be filled
with unnecessary troubles, won't they?
I am different.
Having lived outside the palace
all these years,
I have experienced the myriad changes
of the world
and seen all kinds of people.
No matter what kind of lady or scheme,
they are useless against me.
I can also be certain
that in this world,
no one else but the Commandery Princess
can move my heart.
But if you...
Won't my sister end up lonely
for the rest of her life?
If she marries another prince,
she will never be able
to leave the imperial capital.
But if I truly have a short life,
she can leave the imperial capital
and return to northwest.
If she meets a man she likes,
she can marry again.
Your family
can live a peaceful and happy life.
Looking at it this way,
am I, your future brother-in-law,
much more pleasing to the eye?
I know what you say makes sense.
But I have one more question.
How did you know we would run into
Prince Ning and Shen Yingruo today,
as well as Prince Lie and Gu Qingshu?
I am no fortune-teller.
I only knew that in the palace,
it's rare to gather so many princes
and noble ladies
all in one place.
Those with ulterior motives
wouldn't miss such a great opportunity.
It really was just a coincidence?
Or rather, good luck.
Even Heaven intends
to bring about this good marriage
between Commandery Princess and me.
I find that
I've fallen into another
carefully dug trap of yours.
What's more terrifying is that
after falling in,
I don't even feel
there's anything wrong with it.
Young Master Shen,
what I want to give Xihe
is love and understanding.
I will treat every day
as if it were my last,
devoting myself to her wholeheartedly.
I will make every season bright for her,
and be with her day and night.
If you can truly keep your word,
I can persuade my father.
Not a single word is false.
From now on,
we are family.
I will return to the northwest soon.
My sister
is entrusted to you, Your Highness.
It's not an entrustment.
The Commandery Princess
is someone who can stand
shoulder to shoulder with men,
and is even
wiser and decisive than them.
- Greetings, Father.
- Greetings, Your Majesty.
You may rise.
The marriage between you two
has received the approval
of Duke of Wei and Young Master Shen.
Father,
all these years,
while recovering from my illness,
I felt my days were dark and hopeless.
But Xihe didn't shy away from me.
She personally attended
to my every need.
Among all my talented
and handsome brothers,
she favored me, a sickly man.
Her affection and care
are the best medicine.
Having met such a wonderful lady,
I will marry no one but her.
Your Majesty,
the Crown Prince and I
share the same interests.
We are deeply in love.
His appearance, intellect,
character, and demeanor,
as well as his gentle nature,
are truly unparalleled in this world.
I will marry no one but him.
I'm not that perfect.
In my heart, you are the best.
Of all the men in this world,
only you
can give me the joy
of mutual understanding and devotion.
I want to walk hand in hand with you,
year after year,
for the rest of our lives.
Good.
Excellent.
Xihe, Huayong,
the two of you are kindred spirits
and deeply in love.
It is truly rare.
I grant this marriage.
After the Jiuxiao Festival,
I will officially decree your marriage.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
- Thank you, Father.
If she sees it,
she will know
that I am the one
with the Tagara incense.
I am not the man she thinks I am,
a Crown Prince with no backing.
You are that Tagara Incense.
You never believed
in my true feelings for you.
What do true feelings matter?
How many true feelings
change in an instant
when faced with conflicts of power?
I ask Your Highness to cooperate
and break off our engagement.
I will never allow you
to marry anyone else.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)